Alfred I. Hallowell Papers 1892-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.26
American Philosophical Society
- Series III - Works by Hallowell, 1917-1974 (Box 13-18)
  - "The Personality Structure of Saulteaux Children", [1930s]; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - "Pigeon River People", [ca. 1937]; 4 folders (Box 16)
    -Photo removed to Ser.VI, G
  - "'Popular Responses and Cultural Differences: An Analysis Based on Frequencies in a Group of American Indian Subjects" (Box 16)
  - Primitive Social Organization by Elman R. Service--Review, [1962] (Box 16)
  - "The Problem of Fish Nets in North America", 1920; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - [Property], [ca. 1940s]; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - "Psychological Aspects of Human Existence"--Lecture, 21 July 1955 (Box 16)
  - "The Psychological Dimensions of Human Evolution", n.d. (Box 16)
  - Psychology: A Study of a Science edited by Sigmund Koch--Review, [1959] (Box 16)
  - Pueblo Indian Religion by Elsie Clews Parsons--Review, 1939 (Box 16)
    Reviewed with: The Menomini Indians of Wisconsin by Felix M. Keesing, Tsimshian Clan and Society by Viola E. Garfield, Shamanism in Western North America by Willard Z. Park, Bantu Heritage by H.P. Junod, Prophecy and Divination Among the Hebrews and Other Semites by Alfred Guillame, Studies in Popular Islam by Samuel M. Zwemer
  - "Qualitative Analysis of Research Records of Four Age Groups of Flambeau Children", n.d. (Box 17)
  - The Racial Characters of the Swedish Nation by H. Landberg and F.J. Linders--Review (Box 17)
  - "Racial Discrimination"--Lecture, 1942 (Box 17)
  - "The Role of Dreams in Ojibwa Culture", 1962; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - "The Role of Dreams in the Ojibwa Sociocultural System", n.d. (Box 17)
  - "Rorschach Investigation--Berens River Saulteaux", n.d. (Box 17)
  - "The Rorschach Test in Personality and Cultural Studies", 4 folders (Box 17)
  - "Rorschachs of 151 Berens River Saulteaux (Ojibwa) Adults and Children and 115 Lac du Flambeau Adults", 1957; 7 folders (Box 17-18)
  - [Sacrificial Offerings], n.d. (Box 18)
  - Savage Civilization by Tom Harrison--Review, [1937] (Box 18)
  - Selected Writings of Edward Sapir-- Review, 1950 (Box 18)
  - "The Self and Its Behavioral Environment", 1951 (Box 18)
  - "Signs and Symbols" (Box 18)
  - "Some Psychological Aspects of Measurement Among the Saulteaux", n.d. (Box 18)
  - "The Spatial Orientation of the Saulteaux", n.d. (Box 18)
  - "Speculations on Some Cultural Links Between Ancient China and North America"--Lecture, 1938 (Box 18)
  - The Study of Man by Ralph Linton--Review, [1936] (Box 18)
  - Theories of Personality by Calvin S. Hall and Gardner Lindzey--Review, [1957] (Box 18)
  - "To Nigeria", 1961 (Box 18)
  - "Values, Acculturation and Mental Health"--Lecture, 1950 (Box 18)
  - "Variations in Sexual Behavior in Different Cultures"--Lecture, [1955] (Box 18)
  - Walapai Ethnography by Fred Kniffen et al.--Review, 1938 (Box 18)
  - "War as a Factor in Natural Selection", 1917 (Box 18)
  - We, the Tikopia by Raymond Firth--Review, 1937 (Box 18)
  - Where the Two Came to Their Father by Jeff King--Review, [1943] (Box 18)
  - "The Windigo Psychosis" (Box 18)
  - Yale University Publications in Anthropology-- Review, 1937 (Box 18)
- Series IV - Works by Others, 1923-1976 (Box 19-21)
  Series IV - Works by Others
  contains notes and articles written by Hallowell's students and professional colleagues. The authors best represented are William A. Caudill, who studied the Ojibwa, and Blanche Green Watrous, who administered Rorschach Tests to Native American children in the Lac Du Flambeau and Berens River areas. This series is arranged alphabetically by author and then by title.
  - National Character Studies, 1947; Ackerknecht, Erwin Heinz, 1906-1988 (Box 19)
  - Methodology in the Social Sciences, 1940; Aginsky, Burt W. (Box 19)
  - Child Training in Cross-Cultural Perspective, 1959; Albert, Jenny (Box 19)
  - Coiled Basketry in British Columbia, n.d.; Andresen, Elisabeth (Box 19)
  - Literature as a Cultural Model, [1968]; Arbuckle, John (Box 19)
  - The Reservation Situation and Personality: the Chippewa Case, 1962; Barnouw, Victor (Box 19)
  - Some Notes and Queries, 1934; Beaglehole, Pearl, 1910-1979 (Box 19)
    [on Personality and Cultural in the Polynesian Community, Pukapuka]
  - Relationship Between Religious and Economic Organization of the Pomo Indians, Bell, Harriett Prescott (Box 19)
  - Social Organization of the Zuni and Navajo Indians, Boothe, Irene E. (Box 19)
  - The Selection of Cases for Small Social Science Studies, 1942; Burgess, E. W., (Ernest Watson), 1886-1966 (Box 19)
  - Nuer Spacis-Temporal Concepts, 1953; Caine, Shulamith Wechter (Box 19)
  - Position and Work of Women in the League of the Iroquois, 1934; Calhoun, N. N. (Box 19)
  - The Status of the Iroquois Women, [1934]; [Calhoun, N. N.] (Box 19)
  - Economics of the Hopi Indians, 1937; Cannon, Emily P. (Box 19)
  - Aivilik Eskimo Time-Space Concepts, 1950; Carpenter, Edmund, 1922-2011 (Box 19)
  - ...As I Recall: the Autobiographies of Two Ojibwa Indians, 2 folders; Caudill, William A. (Box 19)
  - Psychological Characteristics of Acculturated Wisconsin Ojibwa Children, 1948; Caudill, William A. (Box 19)
  - Drawing as a Prospective Method in the Study of Personality and Culture, Coelho, Ruy Galvao de Andrade, 1920-1990 (Box 19)
  - World-View Analysis, n.d.; Cole, John R. (Box 19)
  - Hallowell's Bear Ceremonialism and the Emergence of Boasian Anthropology, [ca. 1976]; Darnell, Regna (Box 19)
  - Oral Tradition as Complement, 1968; Day, Gordon M. (Box 19)
  - "Der Heilbringer" -- Translation, 1931; Deursen, A. van, (Arie), 1891-1963 (Box 19)
  - The Origin, History and Distribution of Maize, 1930; Dickerson, Hildred (Box 19)
  - Basketry of the Tlingit Indians, Diehl, Stenger (Box 19)
  - The Origin of Races by Charleton S. Coon -- Review, 1962; Dobzhansky, Theodosius Grigorievich, 1900-1975 (Box 19)
  - The Acquistion of New Social Habits, 1944; Dollard, John, 1900-1980 (Box 19)
  - Social Stratification as Presented in the American Anthropologist, 1954; Feiertag, Erwin L. (Box 20)
  - Art Styles and Cultural Cognitive Maps, 1959; Fischer, John L. (Box 20)
  - Cultural Determinants of Logical Process, 1959; Gladwin, Thomas, b. 1916 (Box 20)
  - Social Organization of the Tlingit and Haida Report for Primitive Society, 1929; Hall, W. Scott, (William Scott), b. 1905 (Box 20)
  - [Social Organization of the Kwakiutl Indians], 1929; Hall, Warren (Box 20)
  - The Problem of Racial Psychology, 1923; Hallowell, Dorothy Kern (Box 20)
  - Some Aspects of Navaho Space and Time, Hastings, Virginia (Box 20)
  - Anthropology in the General Social Science Course, 1949; Henry, Jules (Box 20)
  - A Consideration of Cultural Fallacies, 1948; Highland, Genevieve A. (Box 20)
  - Culture and Personality, Hobbs, A. H. (Box 20)
    -With "Endocrinology--Its Place in Study of Personality"
  - The Eastern Cherokee and the Hypothesized Core Traits of American Indians, 1957; Holzinger, Charles H. (Box 20)
  - Discussion of a Paper by Alex Inkeles and Daniel J. Levinson, 1954; Honigmann, John J. (Box 20)
  - Seminoles, 1923; Hopkins, Grace (Box 20)
  - The Susquehannocks, 1924; Hopkins, Grace (Box 20)
  - Chaco Reports, n.d.; Howard, G. D. (Box 20)
  - Field Project in Acculturation, 1961; Kayser, Joyce (Box 20)
  - [Theories of Totemism], 1936; Knowles, N[athaniel?] (Box 20)
  - Normal Eskimo Demes and Personality, 1960; Kutsche, Paul, b. 1927 (Box 20)
  - Red and White Highlanders, 1958; Kutsche, Paul, b. 1927 (Box 20)
  - Plains Indian Art, 1928; Lakoff, Elsie (Box 20)
  - Aracanian Social Organization, n.d.; Leslie, C. J. (Box 20)
  - Historiography, Ethnohistory, and Applied Anthropology, 1955; Lurie, Nancy Oestreich (Box 20)
  - The Social Organization of the Tribes of the North Pacific Coast, n.d.; McCann, Catherine (Box 20)
  - The Midwestern Taxonomic Method as an Aid to Archaeological Culture Study, [ca. 1940]; McKern, W. C., (Will Carleton), 1892- (Box 20)
  - Research on Americans of Mexican Descent, [1958]; Macklin, Barbara June (Box 20)
  - Prediction, Causality, and the Constructed Type, Martindale, Don (Box 20)
  - The Mother, the Ego, and Mental Health, 1961; Meredith, Dorothy A. (Box 20)
  - An Attempt at Understanding: A Critical Review of Sex, Custom and Psychopathology, 1937; Monahan, Thomas P. (Box 20)
  - The Economic System of the Kiwai Papuans of British New Guinea, 1937; Mook, Wendell E. (Box 20)
  - Primitive Economics -- Bedouins of Arabia, 1940; Mooney, Olive A. (Box 20)
  - Primitive Economics of the New Zealand Maori, Muller, Henry M. (Box 20)
  - The Origin and Development of Eskimo Culture, Newman, Raymond S. (Box 20)
  - Some Cultural Aspects of the Menomini, [1932]; Newman, Raymond S. (Box 20)
  - Zuni Religion, 1942; Noble, Olive A. M. (Box 20)
  - The Relationship Between Categories and Perception, Nutall, Sue (Box 20)
  - Facing New Tasks: Cree and Ojibwa Children's Adaptation to Residential School, Preston, Richard J. (Box 20)
  - Cultural Evolution in Modern American Anthropology: An Analysis of the Work of Julian H. Steward and Leslie A. White, 1959; Radetsky, Henry (Box 21)
  - Acculturation of the Far-West Frontiersmen, n.d.; Raemsch, Bruce E. (Box 21)
  - The Indianization of Mountain Men, [ca. 1965]; Raemsch, Bruce E. (Box 21)
  - Clinical and Statistical Illnesses in Thailand: Chapter IV Schizophrenia, 1955; Ratanakorn, Prasop (Box 21)
  - The Role of Ego in Behavior Pathology, 1952; Rausch, Norman L. (Box 21)
  - The Concept of Culture in Sociological Textbooks, 1954-1955; Reeves, Earl Y. (Box 21)
  - Culture and Mental Disorders, 1954-1955; Reeves, Earl Y. (Box 21)
  - Spatio-Temporal Orientation of the Amassalik Eskimos, n.d.; Ricciardelli, Alex F. (Box 21)
  - Llingir Basketry, n.d.; Risser, Eleanor L. (Box 21)
  - Franz Boas Among the Kwakiutl, 1965; Rohner, Ronald P. (Box 21)
  - On the Psychology of North African Jewish Children and Youth, 1949; Salomon, Fritz (Box 21)
  - Psychological Observation Amongst the 200 Children Going to Norway, 1949; Salomon, Fritz (Box 21)
  - Hopi Material, 1940; Schafer, Ann (Box 21)
  - An Experiment in the Application of the Wiese-Becker System of Sociological Analysis to a Concrete Study of the Nature and Function of the Choral Society in American Social Life, Schmid, Robert (Box 21)
  - Social Systems of Africa by Richard Thurnwald, [ca. 1930]; Solenberger, [Robert Reeves] (Box 21)
  - The Spatio-Temporal Orientation of the Bedouin Arabs, 1952; Stout, Howard W., Jr. (Box 21)
  - The Winnebago Indians, Thompson, Anna R. J. (Box 21)
  - Early Childhood Experience With Relationship to Personality and Ego Development, 1959; Tiffany, Elizabeth G. (Box 21)
  - Summary of Navajo Mythology, n.d.; Trotter, Elizabeth (Box 21)
  - The Allegory of Love by C. S. Lewis -- Review, [ca. 1940?]; Unidentified (Box 21)
  - The Material Culture of the Hopi Indians, Unidentified (Box 21)
  - Preliminary Analysis of Ten Rorschach Protocols From Painttown Community, n.d.; Unidentified (Box 21)
  - Proposal for Research in Belgium, 1962-1963; Unidentified (Box 21)
  - [Proposal for Research in Northern Italy], Unidentified (Box 21)
  - Cross-Cultural Study of the Etiological Factors of Disease, 1959; Vart, Janet L. (Box 21)
  - Impressions of Lac Du Flambeau Indian Children, Watrous, Blanche Green (Box 21)
  - Summary of Rorschach Test Results of 102 Flambeau and 49 Berens River Children, Watrous, Blanche Green (Box 21)
  - A Concordance to Cree Mythology, 1932; Wepley, Margaret Noyes (Box 21)
  - The Perception of Direction, n.d.; Werntz, John D. (Box 21)
  - The American Indian and American Culture, 1959; White, Philip L. (Box 21)
  - The Effect of Acculturation on the Pottery Complex in the Pueblo Village of San Idlefonso Since 1890, n.d.; Wielitz, Esther Kathryn (Box 21)
  - The Religion of the Indian Tribes of the Great Plains, 1938; Wilson, J. Wayne (Box 21)
  - The Foundations of Social Institutions, Woodward, James W. (Box 21)
    -With Crawford, W. Rex "The Development of Moral Standards"
  - A Critique of A. Hallowell's The Self and Its Behavioral Environment, 1955; Zeleznik, Carter (Box 21)
- Series V - Research Files, 1892-1964 (Box 22-38)
  Series V - Research Files
  contains field and reading notes taken by Hallowell, his students, and colleagues; as well as some course materials. The bulk of the field notes include ethnological observations, folklore, Rorschach Tests, and drawings of the Ojibwa-speaking Native Americans in Canada (Berens Rivers Saulteaux) and Lac du Flambeau, Wisconsin. Other major subjects of this series include the Abenaki, marriage and the family, nets and netting, bear cult, self and ego, and Rorschach methodology and materials. The earliest dates in this series refer to the dates of publications from which Hallowell made reading notes. These notes concern general aspects of the history and culture of Native North Americans, as well as clippings depicting them in Euro-American art and literature. This series is arranged alphabetically by subject, and the folder labels reflect Hallowell's original spelling and wording, e.g., terms such as "Indian" are retained. Materials filed under the same label in consecutive folders were kept in the original order in which they were received; thus, materials may not appear in order by date. Also included in this series are three card file boxes. Box 1 contains cards on Ojibwa families of Lac du Flambeau, Wisconsin, which note the names of family members, their birth dates, and their tribal affiliations. Cards are arranged alphabetically by family surname, and each family member listed under the surname has been assigned a serial number. At the end of the alphabetical arrangement, individual family member cards are arranged numerically by serial number. Box 1 also contains reading notes on the history of Native Americans in Wisconsin, as well as a bibliography of Ojibwa myths and tales. Box 2 contains a Rorschach bibliography. Cards are arranged according to topics, e.g., "Children," "Aptitude and Talent," and "Special Studies." Box 3 contains a bibliography of literature concerning Native Americans. Cards are arranged first by topic, e.g., "Short Story," "Dime Novel," and "Captivity Stories." Authors of works under each topic are then filed alphabetically.
  - Abenaki Indians, [1920s]; 7 folders (Box 22)
  - Abenaki Indians--Agriculture and Plants, [1920s] (Box 22)
  - Abenaki Indians--Animals, [1920s] (Box 22)
  - Abenaki Indians--General Ethnology, [1920s] (Box 22)
  - Abenaki Indians--History, [1920s]; 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Abenaki Indians--Hunting Territories and Family Names, [192-]; 2 folders (Box 22)
    -Photo removed to Ser.VI, F339
  - Abenaki Indians--Kinship Terms, [1920s]; 4 folders (Box 22-23)
  - Abenaki Indians--Measurements and Genealogical Data, [1920s]; 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Abenaki Indians--Medical Practices, [1920s]; 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Abenaki Indians--Narrative Folklore, [1920s] (Box 23)
  - Abenaki Indians--Plant and Animal Charts, [1920s] (Box 23)
  - Abenaki Indians--Specimens Collected, 1914-1927 (Box 23)
  - [Abenaki and Other Material] (Box 23)
  - Adam Big Mouth and Windigo -- Field Notes, 1938 (Box 24)
  - Affective, [1930s-1940s] (Box 24)
    [Emotions]
  - Africa, 1918-1923, [ca. 1935] (Box 24)
  - Aggression, 1936, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Algonkian--Cross-Cousin Marriages, 1930 (Box 24)
  - The American Indian in Painting and Sculpture, [1950s]; 4 folders (Box 24)
  - American Indians, 9 folders (Box 24)
    - Folder 1, 1930, n.d. (Box 24)
    - Folder 2, 1940-1941, 1946 n.d. (Box 24)
    - Folder 3, 1946-1947 (Box 24)
    - Folder 4, [ca. 1940s] (Box 24)
    - Folders 5 - 7, [1920s-1940s] (Box 24)
    - Folders 8 - 9, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Animals and Religion, 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Antiquity of Man in America and Chronology, [ca. 1940s]; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Araucanian Indians--Kinship (Box 25)
  - Australia, n.d.; 3 folders (Box 25)
  - Behavioral Environment, [1940s-1960s]; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Canada--Map, [1924?] (Box 25)
  - Canoes, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Cartography, 1948, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Causation, [1930s] (Box 25)
  - Ceramics, n.d.; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Cherokee--Children's Drawings, [1944?]; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Coiled Basketry, 1932, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Conscious Thought and Reasoning (Box 26)
  - Course Bibliographies, [1930s?] (Box 26)
  - Cree--Ethnological Notes from Historic Sources, n.d.; 2 folders (Box 26)
    -Photo removed to Ser.VI, F333
  - Cultural Dynamics, [1920s-1930s]; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Culture and Psychology--Course Notes, 1943 (Box 26)
  - Demography, [1930s-1940s] (Box 26)
  - Dreams, [1950s?]; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - [Dreams, Fasting, and Sanctions], 1962, n.d. (Box 26)
  - Early Man, [1930-1940]; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Eastern Woodlands, 1920s-1930s (Box 26)
  - Economics, n.d.; 3 folders (Box 27)
  - Eskimos, [ca. 1930s] (Box 27)
  - [Eskimos], 1937 (Box 27)
    Fragile newspaper
  - Eskimos--Myth Analysis, n.d. (Box 27)
  - Family (Sociology IV), n.d.; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Field Notebooks, 1930-1932 (Box 27)
  - Indian in Literature, 2 folders (Box 27)
    -See also Ser.V, Indians in Literature card file
    - Folder 1, 1953-1958, n.d. (Box 27)
    - Folder 2, [1960], n.d. (Box 27)
  - Indian Linguistics, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - Folder 1, 1935, n.d. (Box 27)
    - Folder 2, n.d. (Box 27)
  - [Kinship and Lineage Charts] (Box 27)
  - Language, n.d. (Box 27)
    includes notes on:
    European Immigrants, European Races, Fire, Cultural Evaluation, Human Behavior and Culture, Tools
  - [Linguistics], n.d. (Box 27)
  - M & M Sentence Completion Test, n.d. (Box 28)
  - Marriage, [1930s] (Box 28)
  - Marriage and the Family--Ethnographic Notes by Students, 2 folders (Box 28)
    - Folder 1, 1927, 1928 (Box 28)
    - Folder 2, 1927 (Box 28)
  - Marriage and the Family--Notes, 1927, n.d. (Box 28)
  - [Masai], n.d. (Box 28)
  - Melancholia, [1930s] (Box 28)
  - Metalwork and Stonework (Box 28)
  - Methodology, [1940s] (Box 28)
  - [Mohegan Vocabulary and Text; Falls River Indian Reservation; Iroquois; Other Ethnology Notes], 1892, 1904, n.d. (Box 28)
  - Nets and Netting, [ca. 1920s]; 8 folders (Box 28)
    -Photos removed to Ser.VI, F336 - 337
  - Nets and Netting--Asia and Pacific (Box 28)
  - Nets and Netting--Athabascan, [ca 1920s] (Box 28)
  - Nets and Netting--Eastern Woodlands, [ca 1920s] (Box 28)
    -Photo removed to Ser.VI, F330
  - Nets and Netting--Eskimos, [ca. 1920s]; 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Nets and Netting--Linguistics, [1920s] (Box 29)
  - Nets and Netting--Maps, [ca 1920s] (Box 29)
  - Nets and Netting--Northwest Coast, 2 folders (Box 29)
    -Photos removed to Ser.VI, F328 - F329
    - Folder 1, [1928, n.d.] (Box 29)
    - Folder 2, [ca 1920s] (Box 29)
  - New England Wabanaki--Bibliography (Box 29)
  - Northwest Coast (Box 29)
    [Indians]
  - Ojibwa (Chippewa)--Ethnology, [ca 1940s] (Box 29)
  - Ojibwa Indians, 3 folders (Box 29)
    - Folder 1, [ca 1940s] (Box 29)
    - Folder 2, 1940, n.d. (Box 29)
    - Folder 3, [ca 1940s] (Box 29)
  - Ojibwa Indians--Kinship Terms, [ca 1940s] (Box 29)
  - Ojibwa Indians--Myths and Tales, 3 folders (Box 29)
    - Folders 1 - 2, n.d. (Box 29)
    - Folder 3, 1938 (Box 29)
  - Ojibwa Indians--Rorschach Tests, [ca 1940s]; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Ojibwa Indians--Vocabulary (Box 29)
  - Ojibwa Indians (Flambeau), 15 folders (Box 29-30)
    -Photo removed to Ser.VI, F332
    - Folder 1, [1946?] (Box 29)
    - Folder 2, 1946 (Box 29)
    - Folder 3, [1946?] (Box 30)
    - Folders 4 - 5, 1946 (Box 30)
    - Folder 6, [1946] (Box 30)
    - Folder 7, 1946 (Box 30)
    - Folder 8, 1945 (Box 30)
    - Folder 9, 1946 (Box 30)
    - Folder 10, [1946] (Box 30)
    - Folder 11, 1947 (Box 30)
    - Folder 12, 1946, n.d. (Box 30)
    - Folder 13, [1946?] (Box 30)
    - Folder 14, 1946 (Box 30)
    - Folder 15, 1947 (Box 30)
  - Ojibwa Indians (Flambeau)--Drawings, 1943; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Ojibwa Indians (Flambeau)--Rorschach Test, 5 folders (Box 30)
    - Folder 1, 1944, n.d. (Box 30)
    - Folder 2, 1946 (Box 30)
    - Folder 3, [1946?] (Box 30)
    - Folder 4, 1946 (Box 30)
    - Folder 5, [1946?] (Box 30)
  - Ojibwa Indians (Flambeau)--Student Reports, 1946 (Box 31)
  - Ojibwa Indians (Flambeau)--Thematic Apperception Test, 1946 (Box 31)
  - Pictographs, n.d. (Box 31)
    -See also Ser. VI, A82
  - Plains, 1922, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Pottery, 1940, n.d. (Box 31)
    -Photos removed to Ser.VI, F334 - F335
  - Prehistory, n.d.; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Race, [ca. 1940s] (Box 31)
  - Religion, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Religion--Animal Cults, n.d. (Box 31)
  - Religion--Bear Cult, 6 folders (Box 31-32)
    - Folders 1 - 2, [1950s?] (Box 31)
    - Folders 3 - 4, n.d. (Box 31)
    - Folders 5 - 6, n.d. (Box 32)
  - Remembering, 1939, n.d. (Box 32)
  - Rorschach Test, 20 folders (Box 32-33)
    - Folder 1, 1938-1940, n.d. (Box 32)
    - Folder 2 - 4, n.d. (Box 32)
    - Folder 5 - 8, 1940, n.d. (Box 32)
    - Folder 9, 1938-1940, n.d. (Box 32)
    - Folder 10, 1939-1940, n.d. (Box 32)
    - Folder 11, 1940 (Box 33)
    - Folder 12, n.d. (Box 33)
    - Folder 13, 1942, n.d. (Box 33)
    - Folder 14, n.d. (Box 33)
    - Folder 15, 1947-1949, n.d. (Box 33)
    - Folder 16, 1951-1952, n.d. (Box 33)
    - Folder 17 - 19, n.d. (Box 33)
    - Folder 20, 1938-1939, n.d. (Box 33)
  - Rorschach Test--Fijians, 1939, n.d. (Box 33)
  - Rorschach Test--India?, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Rorschach Test--Manus (Admiralty Islands) Native, 1956 (Box 33)
  - Rorschach Test--Materials, n.d. (Box 33)
  - Rorschach Test--Methodology, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Rorschach Test--Moslems, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Rorschach Test--"Notes", n.d.; 4 folders (Box 34)
  - Rorschach Test--Popular Responses, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Rorschach Test--Primitive People, n.d. (Box 34)
  - Rorschach Test--White Children, 1940 (Box 34)
  - [St. Francis Indian Reservation and Other Materials], 1925, n.d. (Box 34)
    -Photo removed to Ser.VI, F338
  - Saulteaux Indians, 3 folders (Box 34)
  - Saulteaux Indians--Chief William Berens' Autobiography, 1940 (Box 34)
  - Saulteaux Indians--Conjuring, Shamanism (Box 34)
  - Saulteaux Indians--Dreams (Box 34)
  - Saulteaux Indians--Intra-Group Variability (Box 34)
  - Saulteaux Indians--Island Lake (Box 35)
  - Saulteaux Indians--Myths and Tales, 29 folders (Box 35-36)
    - Folder 1, 1932-1933, 1936, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 2, 1936, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 3, 1930-1934, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 4, 1933-1934, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 5, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 6, 1932-1938 (Box 35)
    - Folder 7, 1930-1934, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 8, 1932-1938, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 9 - 10, 1936, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 11, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 12, 1936-1940, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 13, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 14, 1938, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 15, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 16, 1939, n.d. (Box 35)
    - Folder 17, 1936-1938, n.d. (Box 36)
    - Folder 18, n.d. (Box 36)
    - Folder 19, 1932-1936, n.d. (Box 36)
    - Folder 20, 1925-1938, n.d. (Box 36)
    - Folder 21, 1930-1936, n.d. (Box 36)
    - Folder 22, 1932-1938, n.d. (Box 36)
    - Folders 23 - 26, n.d. (Box 36)
    - Folder 27, 1925, n.d. (Box 36)
    - Folders 28 - 29, n.d. (Box 36)
  - Saulteaux Indians--Neurotic Signs (Box 36)
  - Saulteaux Indians--Neurotic Signs--Windigo, 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Folder 1, [1936], n.d. (Box 36)
    - Folder 2, 1933, 1947 (Box 36)
  - Saulteaux Indians--Rorschach Test, 5 folders (Box 36-37)
    - Folder 1, 1940, n.d. (Box 36)
    - Folder 2, n.d. (Box 36)
    - Folders 3 - 5, n.d. (Box 37)
    - Erlebnistypus, 1935, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Saulteaux Indians--Social Customs and Organization, 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Folder 1, 1930, n.d. (Box 37)
    - Folder 2, 1931-1940 (Box 37)
  - Schoolcraft, [Henry R.], [1946] (Box 37)
  - Self and Ego, 8 folders (Box 37)
    - Folders 1 - 6, 1912, 1934-1964 (Box 37)
    - Folders 7 - 8, n.d. (Box 37)